That naive day of my youth...
...when I...
...had to face the truth of this world.
"That Day"
Sync and corrections by masaca
- addic7ed.com -
Move it, you vermin.
What, more devil-bloods?
Damn Eldians crawling
around as they please.
Grisha...
It's all right. Aren't you used to it?
Look.
It's right over that bank.
It's so big...!
Have you come to see the airship, too?
Huh? Uh, yes...
You from the Liberio Internment Zone?
Let's see your exit permit.
Huh? Um...
I don't have one.
You entered the city without permission?
- You know what that means, right?
- Yes.
Labor or beating. Which is it?
A beating...
- Grisha!
- Oh?
You don't want to
trouble your parents?
Yes.
I forced my sister to come with me!
Please give her punishment to me, too!
Very well.
Grisha!
Here's another!
Man, go easy on him, Kruger.
Come on. Let's get you on your way home.
It was smart not to take off your armbands.
Eldians without one are sent to
their paradise, even if they're kids.
I'll go... home.
Wait.
Didn't you come to see the airship?
Might as well see it.
The following day,
my sister was found in the river.
I showed the girl the Liberio gates
and went on my way.
I'm busy with work, you know.
Eldian kids shouldn't be roaming the city
without permits in the first place.
It seems that your son doesn't
grasp the place of his people.
Shouldn't you be teaching him the sins
that your ancestors committed?
...I knew that man from Marley Public
Security was lying through his teeth.
...If that's not enough to make
him behave, put a collar on him.
He had been slacking off
and was napping on the bank.
He wasn't busy at all.
Though my mother grieved, my father...
Thank you so much for your guidance.
I assure you, I'll teach
my foolish son to know better.
He demeaned himself to the men.
I began to hate that man and my father
so much that it made me dizzy.
But more so, I cursed my own foolishness.
One thousand, eight hundred
and twenty years ago,
our ancestor Ymir Fritz made a contract
with the Devil of All Earth and
obtained the Power of the Titans.
Upon her death, Ymir's spirit
was split into the Nine Titans
who formed the Eldian Empire.
After defeating the great nation of Marley,
they ruled over the continent.
Thus began the Dark Ages...
The Subjects of Ymir called other races
inferior and began to oppress them.
They stole lands and fortunes,
and forced other races to bear their
children to increase their numbers.
Their ethnic cleansing continued
for some 1,700 more years.
But the once great nation of Marley
plotted to subvert Eldia
and its arrogance from within.
They brought seven of the Nine
Titans under their control
and were victorious in the
Great Titan War 80 years ago.
The Eldian King at the time erected
three walls on the island of Paradis
and fled there with many of his people.
Our ancestors were abandoned and
left behind on this continent, but...
The gracious people of Marley
let us live and stay on their land...
My father was talkative for someone
who had just lost their daughter.
He obeyed his master's command
and gladly shamed his own ancestry,
much like he was their dog.
That man was telling lies.
The truth wasn't good for him, so he lied.
Quiet. The walls here are thin.
I bet he's the one who took Fay and...
Silence!
I told you... Our ancestors
did terrible things.
They believed in eugenics
and tried to cleanse...
Fay and I did nothing like that!
We were just walking around!
What is wrong with you?
Are you that eager for all of us
to get shipped off to paradise?
Listen, Grisha...
It doesn't matter that we're not
directly responsible for the sins.
But what we are able to do is live
humble lives within this internment zone.
I'm begging you. Please don't
lead us all to the same fate as Fay.
I wonder who was truly in the wrong.
Was it me or this world?
Okay...
I understand.
Perhaps it was both.
I was ignorant and foolish.
The world, irrational and insane.
I discovered my own path
in life when I was 18.
It was around the time I was
to take over my father's clinic.
What is that wound of yours?
This is proof I'm a patriot.
A patriot?
Your sister was killed by a man
in Marley Public Security.
We have an informant inside
the Marley government.
There are some things you need to hear.
It can't be...!
You're kidding me...!
When I learned the truth of my
sister's death, I swore in my heart...
...that I'd show them
who the real devil was.
That my ancestors had done the right thing.
In order to correct the world again,
Eldia would have to be restored.
Our informant in the Marley
government was called "the Owl."
He led the Restorationists
without ever showing himself.
Look! This is the truth!
Our founder Ymir awakened
the Power of the Titans...
Cultivated the wilds... Built roads...
And bridged the mountains!
She helped the people prosper
and develop this entire continent!
The history we were taught is just
a convenient deception for Marley!
Impressive, Grisha...
...You can read this ancient language.
No... I still haven't
deciphered most of it.
Then how did you know the truth?
Isn't it staring us in the face?
I know it because I believe
in our founder Ymir!
We're the chosen children of God!
The Subjects of Ymir!
Yeah!
Comrades! The Owl sent us somebody!
Nice to meet you, everyone.
My name is Dina Fritz.
I'm a descendant of the royal family.
I allowed fate to steer my life
and followed wherever it took me.
She was the last descendant of royal
blood who remained on the continent.
She provided info about the Titans
that only the royal family knew.
This was the break we needed for victory.
I'm sure of it!
The King took the Founding
Titan into the walls!
If we obtain that, we can control all other
Titans and completely annihilate Marley!
But if he could wield a power that
absolute, why did he flee to an island?
That is because he refused to fight.
At the time of the Great Titan War,
the King abandoned his role of
balancing the continent's powers
and moved the capital to a remote island.
And so, these wretched days we live
all began when the King
turned away from conflict.
Let's fight!
The true royal family held their ground
on this continent for the sake of Eldia!
It's time we bring the Founding
Titan back to them!
My comrades! We'll overthrow Marley
and restore the pride of Eldia!
Yeah!
The next year, the two of us married
and were blessed with a son.
His name was Zeke.
A child with royal blood...
Someday, this child will
lead us all to victory...
As time goes on, people change...
As the world around us rapidly advanced...
...a turning point came
for the Restorationists.
Listen up, Eldians!
...We will be selecting warriors from
various zones around the continent!
...The Marley government
needed Subjects of Ymir
...to serve as vessels for the Nine Titans
and become Marleyan warriors.
...If chosen, their family will be granted
the title of Honorary Marleyans and...
According to info from the Owl,
the reason Marley is making a move
is to prepare themselves
for a struggle for resources
as military technology advances.
Though Marley leads the world using
the power of the Seven Titans,
the end of their dominance is nigh.
A massive cache of fossil
fuel lies beneath Paradis,
and gone are the days they can ignore it.
But the King of the walls left this
warning behind 80 years ago...
"If you ever interfere with us,
the millions upon millions of Titans in
the walls will flatten the entire world."
As long as this threat exists,
none dare to confront him.
The thing is, the Marley government
has the same goal as us.
To infiltrate the walls and
recover the Founding Titan.
What do we do?
At this rate...
...Marley will get it before us.
If that happens, Eldia won't see
the light of day again!
No... There's still a way for us...
We'll have my son Zeke...
...become a Marleyan warrior!
Got it, Zeke?
Everything the Marleyans
are telling you is wrong.
But more so than anyone else,
you have to obey exactly what they say.
You're the one who will
save Eldia from disgrace.
Okay... I understand...
But if anyone, I should have known...
How terrible the sin to besmirch
one's beliefs on your children...
Not as a child of royal blood...
Not as the hope of restoring Eldia...
But as my son Zeke, had I ever
thought of him that way?
In any case, Zeke chose to protect
himself and his grandparents...
In exchange for turning in his foolish
parents to Marley Public Security.
We're here.
This is...
...paradise...
That's right.
The penal colony of Eldia
traitors: Paradis Island.
This is where you'll serve
your life sentence...
As a Pure Titan, that is.
Answer me! Who is the Owl?!
Please! No more!
I told you everything! It's true!
That's unfortunate. Let's do another.
I've met you before...
When I was little...
You remember that?
As if I could ever forget
what happened that day...!
Please, just kill me... Don't...
Keep walking!
Please not a Titan...
Grice?
Grisha?! What the hell?!
Why in the world did Zeke
betray us?! He's your son!
I was an idiot to entrust
everything to you!
The Restorationists! Dina, too!
Say something!
I'm sorry...
Why did we let... a guy like you...?
Eldia is finished...
We've got a lively one here.
You're free to go.
Grice!
...Hey! Grice!
...Run straight north!
If you're lucky, you might
make it to the wall!
Sergeant Major Gross?
Hmm? This your first time here?
If we let him run off,
the Titans we're about to make
will chase him down and leave the area.
It won't be long till he's eaten.
Isn't that right, Kruger?
Yeah.
It's him... Without a doubt...
He's the one who killed my sister!
All right!
We've got a bunch to do this time!
Let's get a move on!
Guys...
Don't do it!
Guys!
Stop it! Guys, stop it!
...It's Grice! Can't you see?!
...Kruger! He's so loud, I can't stand it.
...Kruger! He's so loud it's annoying.
I still want to interrogate him a bit.
Continue without me.
Oh? A woman this time? What a waste...
If only you weren't a devil!
Dina...
Darling...
Why are you here? I... I told them
everything there is to know...!
She's a royal...!
Silence!
Could it be... he's trying to cover it up?!
Sheesh. Make him a Titan
to shut him up already.
Grisha, I...
No matter what form I take,
I promise I'll come and find you.
That's lovely. You'll make
a great Titan couple.
Dina!
Where is this?
Who... am I?
Eren, relax!
You're in the stockades.
You and Mikasa are serving
time for insubordination.
Were you having a nightmare, Eren?
Yeah... I was...
You just said... "Who am I?"
Huh?
You did.
Are you crying, Eren?
I feel like... I just woke up
from the longest dream ever.
No... Not a dream...
Memories...
Just now, I was connected
to my dad's memories.
That Titan...
It was you...
Dina...
Look! She's running after Grice
and forgot all about you!
I guess she fancies that guy more than you!
Shut up!
Did you say something?
It's you!
Fifteen years ago, the one who fed my
eight-year-old sister to the dogs was you!
Tsk.
Let me get him off your hands.
You can head back to the ship.
Um, yes, sir.
What was that all about?
The Sergeant Major wants some
time to have fun, rookie.
It's best to leave it at that.
Kruger. Are you done interrogating?
Let's have that lad dance for us.
Dance?
I remember you now, son.
Let's not make you a Titan.
I'll have this one turn into a 3-to 4-meter
Titan so you can fight him.
Why would you... do something like this?
Do you get enjoyment out of
people getting eaten by Titans?
Why, you ask?
Because it's interesting.
Do you think that's a little crazy?
But you know, people actually
want to see cruelty.
Peace can be such a wonderful thing,
but something about it is lacking.
Losing touch with life and death perhaps?
We should live thinking this
might be the last day we've got.
That's the only proper state
of mind for living things.
I'm ready to accept it
when that day comes for me.
That's because I've faced
this cruel world head on
and deepened my understanding of it.
Yeah... It was educational having
my sons' dogs eat your sister.
Do you not feel any remorse?
Well, I get what you're saying.
If something like that happened to one
of my sons, it would crush my heart.
You poor things.
If only you weren't Eldians.
Look. That's your people's true form.
All it takes is some Titan spinal fluid
and you turn into gigantic monsters.
The world needs to wipe out
every last one of you Eldians.
That's the wish of humanity everywhere.
What did you...?
Of course I don't feel remorse.
You're the murderers here.
What were you Restorationists
planning to do to Marley?
Don't you feel any remorse?
It's a lie! I know the truth!
Our founder Ymir helped people
prosper on the continent...
Yeah, whatever.
Since your history is so grand, go and
share it with your friend down below!
Stop it! Don't!
Hear that? Your sister is calling for you!
Dammit!
Well? Is it really that interesting?
You're...
I'm the Owl.
Remember this, Grisha.
A Titan uses their power like this.
Sync and corrections by masaca
- addic7ed.com -
A Titan's power revealed
by Grisha's past...
The men's fierce desire
to pursue freedom...
is passed on to Eren.
Next episode: "Attack Titan."
"Attack Titan"